- Hi, baby.
- Hey.
- Oh, your hair looks nice.
- Oh, thank you.
Much better
than the last time I saw it.
It was all ratty.
Made me want
to stick a match to it.
Uh-huh. You ready to go?
Y-You got everything?
Just let me find my...
Oh, no. I'll drive.
That's...
- Uh-uh.
- You sure?
- Morning, y'all.
- Hey. Good morning, Dad.
- How's retirement treating you?
- Good.
See y'all later.
He's not coming with us?
Uh-uh. He's busy.
Your car is too little.
Let's take mine.
♪ Somebody prayed for me♪
♪ Had me on their mind♪
♪ They took that time
and prayed for me♪
♪ Oh, yes, they did...♪
Can we stop somewhere
and get something to eat?
No time. Got to pick up Grandpa
and Jeanie.
I thought you weren't talking
to Aunt Jeanie anymore.
We started again.
That's good.
She's been keeping Dad.
Grandpa?
Yeah. I don't like it.
Why not?
She's a mess.
She's a hoarder.
Old nasty house.
She just wants Dad
living with her
so she can collect his pension.
She's lost her mind.
♪ Hallelujah...♪
I'm gonna steal him from her.
What? You're gonna
steal him from her?
Mm-hmm. Any time I try to see
him or say hi, she won't let me
unless she's there to supervise.
She has lost her mind.
Lost her damn mind.
Right. That's what I told him.
Mm-hmm. If you want them
to adjust your vacation days,
you got to talk to Nancy in HR.
That's the way I used to do it.
Yeah.
Morning.
No, man.
I'm trying to get like you.
Hey, look,
I'm-a have to let you go.
Yeah, I'm here
to get that new phone.
You know the one
with the night vision?
Yeah.
All right. Take it light.
I'll catch up with you later.
-♪ God is♪
♪ Oh♪
♪ My everything...♪
Can we, um, stop
to get some food real fast?
We'll be late.
Dig in my purse and get you some
cough drops if you're hungry.
I'm okay, thank you.
Thank you, Auntie.
How's your baby, Earn?
Oh, she's good. She's good.
She's, um...
she's not really a baby anymore.
- That's the thing...
- You didn't want
to bring her to church?
She's, uh...
she's with her mom today.
Mm. Hey.
Y'all still ain't married, huh?
You know
they not married, Jeanie.
Hmm.
Well, it's a good thing
you coming to church then, Earn.
You can ask for forgiveness.
Mm-hmm.
For laying
with that beautiful girl
and leaving her in sin.
Aah!
Get the fuck off the road!
Jesus.
♪ Yes, sir, yes, sir,
come on, God is...♪
Let me get Daddy over here.
Ooh. You help me, Earn?
-♪ No matter what♪
♪ You happen to go
through right now♪
♪ Remember that
in the midst of it♪
♪ God only wants to use you♪
-♪ No matter what it is♪
-♪ No matter what♪
♪ That you're going through♪
♪ Hold your head up...♪
You know, it's packed in here.
She probably had to go
to the overflow lot.
Why would she need
to go to the overflow lot?
She has Daddy's handicap pass.
She should be parked by now.
Yeah... um...
You check your phone?
She call you back?
No.
It's your mama.
- It's your mama.
- Yeah.
Yes, it is.
- Yeah, she's a trip.
- Mm-hmm.
She's a real trip. Um...
I got to use the bathroom.
Yeah. This don't make no sense.
Yeah.
Don't make no kind of sense.
Hello?
Hey, Dad.
Hey, what's going on, son?
Yeah, um,
I'm with Mom, and, um,
I think she kind of took Granda
and left me holding the bag
with Aunt Jeanie.
Mm-hmm.
I'm trying to know
how you would handle this.
Really can't answer that.
Taking my day.
I get three hours every Sunday
before the kids show up
at the mall. This is my time.
- It's like that?
- It's like that.
I've been dealing
with this family
for 30 years.
You'll be okay for one day.
I'm sure
you'll do the right thing.
Love you.
Yeah.
John chapter ten,
verse ten says,
"The thief does not come
except to steal
and to kill and to destroy."
I guess you and your mama
must think
I'm stupid, Earn.
What?
I wasn't born yesterday, now.
I watch Criminal Minds,
and I know
when someone's up
to something twisted.
What-what are you talking about?
Your mama stole Daddy,
and you helped her do it.
- No.
- Where did she take him?
- I don't know.
- Earnest.
I don't know, Aunt Jeanie.
I don't know.
What you sneaking
out of church for, then? Hmm?
Where you going?
I'm going to the studio.
I'm supposed
to meet Alfred there. I'm late.
You know, so...
So?
- So?
- So...
So?
So I guess
I'm going to the studio, too.
You're not leaving my sight.
Come on here now.
Sorry, I'm on a schedule.
- Excuse me, sir...
- No. Sorry.
- Not interested.
- Has anyone told you,
you would look really great
in a hat?
Uh... no.
I'm serious.
Not everyone can pull off a hat,
you know,
but you have
a very nice-shaped head.
Well...
I...
- Thank you for that.
- Hey,
I am not going to make you buy
anything, unless you want to.
You seem too strong-willed
for that kind of thing, anyway.
- Brah!
- Yellow.
Again?
- Man, the color yellow, man.
- You cheating.
Nigga, how you cheat
at Uno, man? Hey, y'all...
Y'all ever cheat at Uno?
Anybody know? How you cheat?
You know I don't got
no more yellow cards.
Duh, nigga!
That's the point of the game!
That's how the game is played,
man. That's how you play that.
So, see,
I was trying to be polite,
but now I want you to draw four.
Fuck that.
Eight, nigga,
'cause you out here whining.
I ain't playing
with you no more.
Oh, come on, man, you know I...
- Hey, y'all hear that shit?
-♪ Now they call me Mr. Ruffle♪
♪ 'Cause I'm all
about my chips...♪
...all day until you tell me
where my daddy is, okay?
You think it's gonna be
fun time in the studio?
I don't think so.
Aunt Jeanie?
Out.
Everybody out.
This is a family emergency.
Yeah, come on...
- Let's go, let's go...
- Go on, now, get on!
I'm-a call you, bro.
I'm sorry, man.
Go!
Thank you.
I like your earrings, baby.
Thank you, ma'am.
Mm-hmm.
Hey, look, now, this ain't
got nothing to do with me.
All right? So I don't know
nothing about Aunt Gloria
taking Grandpa, stashing him.
I don't know that.
So you in on this, too, huh?
- She ain't know that?
- No.
Ain't that a "B"?
This whole family is against me.
- Yeah.
- I'll be...
Where'd she take him?
- Why don't you call her? Damn.
- I don't know.
Okay. I-I know what I'm-a do.
I know what I'm-a do.
I'm-a fix y'all. Y'all watch.
- Hello.
- Willy.
Willy, it's Jean.
I need you to add Pearl.
All right.
Hello.
Pearl.
It's Jeanie.
I need you to add Gloria.
What?
Y'all, y'all.
Gloria kidnapped Dad.
Oh, my goodness.
Girl, have you lost your mind?
Look,
you can't kidnap your own dad.
I don't have time to explain it
to you right now,
but the word "kid" is in it.
So, mathematically,
it's impossible.
What? No, she took him!
She sped off with him.
He is confused, and he needs me.
Y'all know he has dementia.
And I'm the only one who knows
how to give him his medicine.
Jeanie,
that man ain't got dementia.
He's just old, just old.
He forgot something
one or two times.
Why don't you just tell her
how to give him his medicine?
I mean, really,
how complicated could it be?
I knew
I couldn't count on y'all.
I knew it.
I mean, this one thing.
And y'all didn't help me pay
for Keisha's college.
- We did, too, help.
All of us did.
- And you didn't help me
sue that crooked mailman,
and you ain't helping me now.
Y'all are bitter towards me.
And don't think
I don't know why.
Why?
Y'all have always hated me.
Ever since we were kids. Because...
Y'all hate me
because I'm light-skinned.
Girl, if you don't get the hell
out of here with all that mess.
Nobody hates you 'cause you're
light-skinned, Your Majesty.
Girl, I hate you
because you're evil.
I bet you won't be complaining
about being light-skinned-ed
if the cops came down there.
What? Oh, I should
call the cops?
- I wish you would.
- Please do.
Uh, do not call the cops, please.
Y'all...
I know exactly
what this is really about.
WILLY [sighs]:
What? What is it about?
It's about Daddy
never remembering Gloria.
I mean, Daddy got kids
all over Georgia,
and he can remember
most of them,
but never little Gloria.
I mean, he didn't remember
her birthday, Christmas,
didn't come to graduation.
And now that he's dying,
you can't even talk to him
because he don't know
who you are.
I bet you haven't even
asked him, have you, Gloria?
That was evil.
You evil.
While I still
got you on the phone,
you do remember
that you owe me $800
for student...
- Yeah.
- I think it definitely might be
my favorite one
that you tried so far.
- You think?
- Mm-hmm.
I mean, it does look
like something I could
wear to play cards
with the guys.
Right, right, right.
Do you want to try
on the number three again?
Yeah.
Does anything
even look bad on you?
You know...
Never mind.
What?
No, you know...
No, come on, tell me.
I have this one hat.
It's not on display,
because it's technically,
it's not for sale yet.
But you are
so handsome and nice,
I think I want
to show it to you.
Okay. Uh, but I don't want to
get you in trouble or anything.
Ah! Trouble.
♪ Love...♪
A special person deserves
a special hat.
Wow.
-♪ Love.♪
- Hmm.
Does your sister have any
history with weapons or drugs?
She might.
She don't. She don't.
Officer... my father
is scared and alone,
and he is confused.
I guarantee you he doesn't even
recognize Gloria.
That's how sick he is.
Okay, hold on.
Can we get your mom
on the phone?
Yeah. Yeah.
Hello.
Hi, Mom. It's Earn.
Um, the cops are here
with Aunt Jeanie.
They need to check on Grandpa.
Hey, can you put
your father on, please?
Hello.
Hello, sir.
We're doing a wellness check.
Is everything okay?
Yeah.
Do you know where you are, sir?
Of course I do.
Are you in any danger?
No.
Ain't no danger here.
Ask him do he know
who he's with.
And do you know
who you're with, sir?
He won't know.
I'm with my daughter.
Gloria.
So, you're not in any danger.
You know where you are
and who you're with, sir?
Yeah.
We're in Egypt.
Been here...
two weeks.
Okay.
Thank you, Officer...
You see that?
Did-did-did you see that?
I told you.
They in Egypt.
♪ There's something
that I want to give you...♪
Hey!
♪ A five-pound box of love♪
♪ With a million-dollar bill
on top♪
♪ Million-dollar bill on top♪
♪ Diamonds on every corner...♪
Oh, my God.
Church is out.
Yo, Pops.
Hold on, man,
let me ask you a question.
What's on your head, Pops?
It's my hat.
And what's wrong
with your hat?
Y'all know what this nigga
remind me of?
You look like--
what's that nigga name, Prince?
This nigga look like Prince.
If Prince never died
and became some old, fat nigga.
Yo, I got to get a picture
of this stupid-ass hat.
I don't think so.
Hey, hey, come...
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
come on, I'm just playing
with you, homie.
Got to get a picture for the,
you know, Gram, like...
Look, I'm late.
I ain't got time for this.
Whoa, come...
Late? What you mean, you late?
You ain't gonna take a picture?
So, I got to beg?
Pops? That's what you want?
I'll do it.
I'm-a beg, Pops.
Begging now, Pops.
On my knees, Pops.
I'm on my knees.
It's what you wanted, ain't it?
Just get up.
As long as I get a picture, I'll
get up, that's all I'm saying.
I'm staying right here.
I'm-I'm cool right here.
- Get up. I'll-I'll take
the picture. Just get up.
- Please?
Oh, you'll take the picture?
Oh, shit.
That's all you had to say, then,
Pops. That's all I wanted...
Man.
Shit about to go viral, Pop.
I like the hat, Pops.
- Excuse me?
- Do you know what...?
She is really not
gonna let us leave, is she?
You normally do wellness checks
over the phone?
You could've took her anywhere,
Earn. Anywhere.
Yeah, and she would've
followed me there.
I was gonna come to you
eventually, relax.
Damn.
Man, I'm just giving you
a hard time, man.
I know. I just...
I just don't want to end up
like them.
What you mean?
Arguing all the time.
Hey.
Hey, yo, uh, miss. Um...
Look, y'all got a-- y'all got
another way out of here?
Like a secret way?
There's another way out back.
Word?
We call it the Shmurda exit.
Bobby had it built when he was
recording here for a month.
He had the FBI
and three baby mamas after him.
Couldn't take any chances.
Didn't help him, though.
- Mm-mm.
- No.
But it might help you.
Yes, I would like
to report a kidnapping.
No, I know
that the cops are here,
but they are not doing
their job, okay?
Wait, nah, nah,
th-this ain't gonna work.
She's gonna see us.
Don't worry, she won't see you.
The only thing is, you can't
look back, not even a glance.
That's how this works.
Can you be here within the hour?
I also need you to arrest
my two nephews.
No, Officer Simone
and-and French,
they're not doing their job.
No, sir.
No, it's-it's a kidnapping.
No, I'm-I'm-- I-I would like
to report a kidnapping, okay?
:
My father has been kidnapped
by my sister.
I know he's not a kid.
Okay, you know, can I speak
to your manager, please?
Mmm. That was good.
Good dinner.
That was not dinner.
Well, what was it, then?
I don't know.
But it's 5:00 p.m.
It's not dinner.
Hey, Pops, you okay?
How was the mall?
You get that phone?
I got it.
It's-it's good.
I hope you didn't
get anything else.
- I didn't.
- Good.
'Cause our Mastercard
last month was too high.
More sweet tea for you, ma'am?
- Oh, I, um...
- No, just the bill.
Yeah, and I can get it.
No, no, I got it, I got it.
- Oh, shoot!
- What?
We didn't get any bread.
Um, excuse me.
Mom, dinner's already over.
We-we don't need the bread.
I mean, we're paying
real money for the food
like everybody else.
We deserve to get bread
And besides, your grandfather
loves that bread.
- Yes, ma'am?
- Oh, we didn't get any bread.
Oh, I'm sorry about that.
Can you maybe bring us some?
Uh, sure. Do you want me
to hang on to the bill?
No, you can bring the bill
and just put the bread
in a to-go box.
Um, let me go check real fast.
"Go check"?
We don't normally
pack bread to go.
You never brought us
any bread in the first place,
so I don't see
how that could be a problem.
There's no problem.
I just got to go ask my boss.
Oh, honey, we could pack
that bread ourselves.
Yeah, but I just got to ask...
Just bring the goddamn bread!
Bring us the bread.
Right. Okay.
Right away, sir. Sorry.
Kids.
Just don't have any respect.
No respect at all.
Y'all want to watch
a Redbox tonight?
Yeah.
♪ We've got to do something,
yeah♪
♪ To save the children♪
♪ Soon it will be their turns♪
♪ To try and save the world♪
♪ Right now they seem to play♪
♪ Such a small part of♪
♪ The things that they'll soon♪
♪ Be right at the heart of♪
♪ My little Tommy♪
♪ He said he wants
to be a fireman.♪
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH